# **Zachary Waldowski**

# **Senior Software Engineer**



A tireless problem-solver with a decade of passion for great software that delights the user. Advising and elevating team members at all experience levels. Maintaining and modernizing code to deliver uncompromising excellence. "Seriously scary" depth of experience in implementation, pitfalls, and years-past fixes.

## **Experience**

Senior Platform Architect, Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2021-Present Providing deep understanding and expertise for clients on iOS. Modernizing and delivering features in product with 2,000,000+ active users. Leading the vanguard of best practices and adopting new technologies.

Solution Architect, Instructor; Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2020-2021 Managing client success from planning to implementation and beyond with a focus on iOS, macOS, and Swift. Authoring and delivering training for SwiftUI and Combine.

Software Developer, Instructor; Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2016-2020 Building innovative iOS and macOS applications. Teaching others around the world to do the same.

Software Developer, Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2013-2016 Delivery and maintenance of market-leading iOS apps under challenging deadlines. Contributions to macOS apps in the B2B environment.

#### **Education**

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA - 2012-2013

Completed 77 credits towards Bachelor of Computer Science. Leave of absence.

Coastal Carolina University, Conway, SC – 2010-2012 Dual-enrollment.

#### **Internships**

Software Developer Intern, Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2013 Internal tooling and project management for iOS and web. Contributions to client products.



#### **Details**

951 Glenwood Ave SE Unit 2105 Atlanta, GA 30316 United States

+1 (843) 333-6836 zach@waldowski.me waldowski.me

On-site, Hybrid, or Remote

### Strengths

- ▶ iOS Development
- ▶ UIKit, Mac Catalyst
- ▶ Swift
- ► SwiftUI
- ► Objective-C
- ► Agile project lifecycle
- ► Technical leadership
- Direct collaboration with stakeholders

#### **Hobbies**

Gaming, Cooking, Traveling